hello welcome to this presentation Java
您好，欢迎来到Java演示文稿
in the wilderkin Tanners I'm Paul
在荒野的Tanners中，我是Paul
Sanders I'm a member of Java platform
Sanders我是Java平台的成员
team and I hack on the core libraries
团队和我一起攻读核心库
java language and hotspots so let's get
Java语言和热点，让我们开始吧
into this presentation
进入这个演讲
okay the jhen for half a day is just two
好吧，詹半天只有两天
things one I'm going to talk about
我要谈论的一件事
running jdk 9 and docker containers and
运行jdk 9和docker容器以及
the second part is I'm going to be
第二部分是我要
reducing the size of JDK 9 in docker
减少Docker中JDK 9的大小
images so I'm going to present some
图片，所以我要介绍一些
slides and I'm going to present some
幻灯片，我将介绍一些
demos on these two aspects before I get
在获得这两个方面的演示之前
into that I just like to point out that
我只是想指出
Java 8 docker images are available for
Java 8 Docker映像可用于
download you can see the links here if
下载您可以在这里查看链接，如果
you want to try those out so let's get
您想尝试一下，让我们开始吧
into the first part of a presentation
进入演示的第一部分
running JDK 9 in docker containers so
在Docker容器中运行JDK 9
we've we've done a bunch of improvements
我们已经做了很多改进
in JDK 9 to honor resource constraints
在JDK 9中遵守资源限制
in docker when you run a docker
当您运行docker时在docker中
container it can be constrained in terms
容器可以在条款上进行约束
of memory and how many CPU sirs have so
的内存以及有多少个CPU先生
the first one we we respect now is si
我们现在尊重的第一个是si
group memory limits that have been set
已设置的组内存限制
by the container and we've added an
通过容器，我们添加了一个
experimental flag here you can see use
实验标记，您可以在这里看到使用
see group memory limit for heap this is
查看堆的组内存限制，这是
experimental at the moment and we hope
目前处于实验阶段，我们希望
that you'll be able to get experience
这样你就能获得经验
running this and then we will switch it
运行它，然后我们将其切换
over to a default setting later on when
稍后再恢复为默认设置
we're comfortable we got this right
我们很舒服，我们做对了
another area that the JDK now respects
JDK现在尊重的另一个领域
is some CPU constraint set for the
是为
container for example runtime available
容器，例如运行时可用
processors will now report their correct
处理者现在将报告其正确的
number of CPUs in the container
容器中的CPU数量
previously used to report the CPUs of
以前用于报告CPU的
the host itself and also we've done some
主机本身，我们也做了一些
fixes to the JVM to make it more stable
修复了JVM，使其更稳定
when resources change for example the
当资源变化时，例如
jiwon garbage collector now operates on
jiwon垃圾收集器现在可以在
active CPU can't discover that JVM
活动CPU无法发现该JVM
startup and not the active CPU count at
启动，而不是处于活动状态的CPU数量
any time it decides it wants to query it
任何时候它决定要查询它
because G 1 needs to size stuff at JVM
因为G 1需要调整JVM的大小
start up correctly based on cpu count it
根据CPU计数正确启动它
sees an ongoing proven so planned for a
看到正在进行的证明如此计划
future release we have a draft JEP in
将来的版本中，我们有一份JEP草案
the works and container aware Java and
工程和容器感知的Java和
we would plan to do a number of
我们将计划做一些
enhancements here for example evaluating
增强功能，例如评估
further support for docker runtime
对Docker运行时的进一步支持
flags you see therefore cpu quotas in
您看到的标志因此在
this there's a lot of work we can do
我们可以做很多工作
here to improve how Java works but now
在这里改善Java的工作方式，但是现在
I'm going to switch to a little demo
我将切换到一个小演示
here and show the resource constraints
在这里并显示资源限制
in action so what I'm going to do is I'm
在行动中，所以我要做的就是
going to run a Java process in a docker
将在docker中运行Java进程
container docker image sorry containing
容器docker图像对不起
Java 9 build and I'm going to run J
Java 9构建，我将运行J
shell as the Java process so let's just
Shell作为Java进程，所以让我们
go ahead and run that so what I'm doing
继续运行，所以我在做什么
is I'm running J shell in a docker
我正在docker中运行J Shell
container it's running Java 9 and we're
容器，它运行的是Java 9，
going to query the the CPU constraint
要查询CPU约束
CPU limits and memory limits to see
CPU限制和内存限制以查看
what's office if first of all I'm
如果我首先是什么办公室
running doc without any constraints it's
没有任何限制地运行文档
just going to run what the defaults are
只是要运行默认值
and and what the host offers up to it so
以及房东提供的服务
we using the runtime get available
我们使用运行时获取
processors we can see that we it reports
处理器，我们可以看到我们报告
this full process is available by
这个完整的过程可以通过
default I've also added some snippets to
默认情况下，我还添加了一些片段
JCL to query the memory limits of both
JCL来查询两者的内存限制
the the Java Runtime and also what's
Java Runtime，还有什么
reported by the C groups and in in the
由C组和中的报告
second case we see unload unloading up a
第二种情况，我们看到卸载了
file here which contains the the the
此处包含的文件
limit in terms of memory that docker
泊坞窗的内存限制
container has here so remember I'm
容器在这里，所以请记住我
running J shell in a container here so
在这里在容器中运行J Shell
if we run the system memory limit let's
如果我们运行系统内存限制，让我们
see what let's see what it offers and it
看看让我们看看它提供了什么
reports it back in megabytes here's as I
报告它以兆字节为单位这是因为我
said that's a huge number basically it's
说这是一个很大的数字
saying docker containers think I don't
说码头集装箱认为我不
care I whatever the host offers me I
照顾我，无论主人提供我什么
will try and use up as much as possible
会尽力用尽
if we look at the the job and limit here
如果我们看工作并限制在这里
for max memory what we have was we is
对于最大内存，我们拥有的是
selecting a 500 megabyte default here so
在这里选择默认的500兆字节
that's with no limits whatsoever set so
没有任何限制
if we switch back and we run a container
如果我们切换回去并运行一个容器
and instead what we're going to do is
相反，我们要做的是
going to limit the docker container to
将docker容器限制为
384 megabytes and limit it so that it
384兆字节并将其限制为
spin to CPU zero so basically one CPU so
旋转到CPU零，所以基本上是一个CPU，所以
let's see what happens when we run that
让我们看看运行该命令时会发生什么
again it's running J shell in a
再次在
container here
这里的容器
let's get the available processes now we
现在我们获取可用的流程
only have one processor available
只有一个处理器可用
compared to four before because we set
与之前的四个相比，因为我们设置了
the restrictor the number of CPU so
限制器的CPU数量
that's working correctly now let's just
现在可以正常工作了
check the system max memory we see it's
检查系统最大内存，我们看到它是
384 because we limited it in the command
384因为我们在命令中限制了它
here like so now let's check for Java
像这样，现在让我们检查一下Java
memory limits here you see well we see
内存限制在这里你会很好我们看到
that Java is ignoring that constraint in
Java忽略了
docker
码头工人
and it's actually trying to grab more
它实际上是在尝试获取更多
memory than is available in the
内存超过
container
容器
now when Java tries to allocate ball
现在，当Java尝试分配球时
memory like this it I think it depends
这样的记忆，我认为这取决于
on the policy of how you run your docker
关于如何运行docker的政策
containers whether the Java process is
容器是否Java进程是
killed or not as soon as it runs out of
一旦耗尽就被杀死或不被杀死
memory and swap so how do we fix this so
内存和交换，所以我们如何解决这个问题
we can use the options that I showed
我们可以使用我显示的选项
earlier the experimental options that we
较早的实验选项
pass into hotspot now you notice they're
进入热点，现在你注意到他们
expressed twice here because of the way
因为方式在这里表达了两次
the implementation Civics of JCL
JCL的实施公民
actually runs to java processes one for
实际上运行到Java进程之一
the repple and one for executing the
repple和一个用于执行
java snippets that we we typed in so
我们键入的Java代码段
let's run that and see what how about
让我们运行它，看看如何
behaves
表现
okay let's get the system memory here it
好吧，让我们在这里获取系统内存
should be free it for before and let's
应该以前免费的，让我们
get the Java max memory here and we see
在这里获取Java最大内存，我们看到了
that it's down to 121 megabytes about a
它下降到121兆字节
third so it's doing the right thing here
第三，所以它在这里做正确的事
it's trying to choose reasonable
它正在尝试选择合理的
defaults of memory uses based on the the
基于的默认内存使用情况
max memory constraints of the container
容器的最大内存限制
itself so you can you can use these
本身，所以你可以使用这些
options you have to add an experimental
您必须添加实验性选项
flag first before you apply the option
在应用选项之前先进行标记
here to use and would be interested in
在这里使用，并会对
feedback of how this works for you when
何时对您有帮助的反馈
running Java and containers ok back to
运行Java和容器就可以了
the second part of my presentation so
我的演讲的第二部分
the second part of a presentation is
演示的第二部分是
reducing the size of JDK 9 and docker
减少JDK 9和docker的大小
images so JDK 9 is modular thanks to
图像，因此JDK 9是模块化的，这要归功于
project jigsaw that's for the major
专为专业设计的项目拼图
release driver of JDK 9 and JDK nine
JDK 9和JDK 9发行版驱动程序
introduces modules to the Java platform
向Java平台介绍模块
so what is a module the module is a set
那么什么是模块，模块是一组
of packages designed for reuse and very
专为重用而设计的软件包
simple definition and modules improve
简单的定义和模块改进
reliability of maintainability of your
您的可维护性的可靠性
programs and we've applied modules to
程序，我们已经将模块应用于
JDK 9 it is itself composed of 79
JDK 9它本身由79个组成
modules we've refactored the whole JDK
我们重构了整个JDK的模块
over a number of years and it now we
多年来，现在我们
find it more reliable and maintainable
发现它更可靠和可维护
itself as well JDK 9 comes with j-link
JDK 9本身也带有j-link
and this is a very interesting tool that
这是一个非常有趣的工具
you can use to create custom Java
您可以用来创建自定义Java
runtimes for example a Java Runtime just
运行时，例如Java Runtime
consisting of the Java based module that
由基于Java的模块组成，
is the module that all other modules
是所有其他模块的模块
depend on so what we can do is we can
依靠，所以我们能做的就是
use a distribution called alpine linux
使用称为alpine linux的发行版
and we can use the work done by the open
我们可以使用公开完成的工作
JDK project Portola to provide a port of
JDK项目为Portola提供了一个端口
a JDK to our pine Linux and specifically
一个JDK到我们的pine Linux，特别是
it's to the muscle C library for alpine
到高山的C肌肉库
Linux users now up in Linux is
现在使用Linux的Linux用户是
interesting because it's a very small
有趣，因为它很小
distribution and it uses muscle C rather
分布，而是使用肌肉C
than lip C to reduce the size of the
比嘴唇C缩小
distribution there early access builds
在那里分发早期访问版本
of the jdk port to alpine linux are
通往linux的jdk端口
available at the link there and the
可在那里的链接和
slides and we can use J link to create
幻灯片，我们可以使用J链接创建
custom Java runtimes for our PI in Linux
Linux中我们的PI的自定义Java运行时
and because our PI Linux is small and we
因为我们的PI Linux很小，所以我们
can create smaller custom
可以创建较小的自定义
Java runtimes it adds for a smaller
它增加了Java运行时
docker image so I'm going to explain how
码头工人的形象，所以我将解释如何
we can do that so first of all I used
我们可以做到这一点，所以我首先使用
when I was running the J shell before I
在我运行J Shell之前
was using a pre-existing image I created
使用的是我创建的现有图像
called JDK 9 Alpine so that was JDK 9 on
称为JDK 9 Alpine，所以JDK 9在
Alpine Linux a full JDK there if we if
如果我们有的话，Alpine Linux会有完整的JDK
we list images here we can see I have
我们在这里列出图像，我们可以看到我有
two images in my docker registry locally
我本地的Docker注册表中有两个图像
I have Alpine Linux which is all of
我有所有的Alpine Linux
about 4 Meg and I have JDK 9 Alpine
大约4兆，我有JDK 9 Alpine
latest which is 356 megabytes so
最新的是356兆字节
basically the whole JDK is about 350
基本上整个JDK大约是350
megabytes in in total so how did I
总兆字节，我怎么
create that JDK 9 image so I have a
创建那个JDK 9映像，所以我有一个
docker file available like so and I want
码头工人文件可用这样，我想要
to build a docker image from that docker
从该泊坞窗构建一个泊坞窗映像
file so what I did was I'm building from
文件，所以我所做的是从
Alpine Linux the docker image for base
Alpine Linux Docker镜像基础
image and I'm adding an EI version of
图片，然后添加EI版本的
JDK 9 for alpine Linux here that I
我在这里针对高山Linux的JDK 9
previously downloaded and I'm basically
以前下载的，我基本上
copying that into the image and setting
将其复制到图像并设置
up some environment variables and I can
一些环境变量，我可以
actually rebuild that image just to show
实际重建该图像只是为了显示
how it works like so and it's a bit
它是如何工作的，有点
faster because I've already built it in
更快，因为我已经内置了它
cache didn't haven't changed anything
缓存没有任何改变
so as there's there's really no change
所以那里真的没有变化
going on here so what I can do is I can
继续在这里，所以我能做的是
run this and show how many modules are
运行它并显示有多少模块
in the JDK called JDK 9 run time by
在名为JDK 9的JDK中运行时
running doing a docker run command and
运行docker run命令并
running Java and listing the modules and
运行Java并列出模块和
we should see there's quite a lot of
我们应该看到有很多
modules here in the full JDK in fact if
完整的JDK中的模块实际上是
we just do a quick count of them we
我们只是对它们进行快速计数
should see there is 79 modules in the
应该看到有79个模块
JDK Nikken if we just scroll through and
JDK Nikken，如果我们只是滚动浏览并
have a look we see there's Java desktop
看看我们看到有Java桌面
javac over here now when you're running
现在，当您运行时，javac在这里
an say a cloud-based application you you
一个说基于云的应用程序
probably don't need desktop and you
可能不需要桌面，您
probably don't need CORBA and you
可能不需要CORBA，而您
probably don't need jdk t perhaps or
可能不需要jdkäôt或
the
的
Javadoc stuff like this so you can strip
这样的Javadoc内容，因此您可以剥离
down your your application just to use
减少您的应用程序以供使用
the jdk modules that you that you
你的jdk模块
require so let's let's try and strip it
需要，让我们尝试剥离它
down to the smallest possible Java
降至最小的Java
Runtime and what we're going to do is
运行时，我们要做的是
I'm going to pick the Java base module
我将选择Java基本模块
the one that all other modules depend on
所有其他模块所依赖的模块
so how are we going to do that so I have
所以我们要怎么做，所以我有
another docker file so first of all we
另一个docker文件，所以首先
need to run j-link that's all I
我需要运行j-link
described earlier and we need to run
如前所述，我们需要运行
j-link
链接
in the container of JDK 9 our plain
在JDK 9的容器中
linux and already have a script for this
linux并且已经有一个脚本
so what this is going to do it's going
所以这将要做的事
to run my JDK 9 alpine container and
运行我的JDK 9高山容器并
it's going to run jailing within that
它会在里面运行监狱
container set up my module path to the
容器设置了我的模块路径
Java modules in the JDK 9 runtime and
JDK 9运行时中的Java模块和
it's going to say I only want to build a
它会说我只想建立一个
new Java runtime that contains the java
包含Java的新Java运行时
base module I'm going to make it smaller
基本模块，我要使其更小
by compressing it I'm going to remove
通过压缩，我将删除
some header files I don't need and then
一些我不需要的头文件，然后
going to output it to this directory
将其输出到此目录
here like so so let's just run this like
这样，所以让我们像这样运行
so while that's running I'm just going
所以在运行的时候我就去
to save some time and copy this command
节省一些时间并复制此命令
here so it's now doing jailing running
在这里，所以现在正在做监狱运行
within the docker container a bit like
在Docker容器中有点像
how we run branch a shell and now it's
我们如何运行一个shell，现在它是
we should see there's a directory here
我们应该看到这里有一个目录
that we created here so that's that's a
我们在这里创建的那是
custom runtime for our pine Linux that
我们的pine Linux的自定义运行时
we just created which is smaller so how
我们刚刚创建了一个较小的
do we put that into a docker file so I
我们是否将其放入docker文件中，所以我
have a docker image so I have another
有一个码头工人形象，所以我有另一个
docker file that we can use to create
我们可以用来创建的docker文件
that docker image which is very similar
该码头工人图像非常相似
to the other one we just basically take
到另一个我们基本上
our custom runtime that we built and
我们构建的自定义运行时
copy into the right location and set up
复制到正确的位置并进行设置
some environment variables so let's just
一些环境变量
build that so now it's going to do some
建立它，所以现在要做一些
actual work here copy this command line
实际工作在这里复制此命令行
while we're waiting here so it's copying
当我们在这里等待时，它正在复制
the directory that's the Java Runtime
Java Runtime的目录
the custom Java Runtime images
自定义Java运行时映像
containing Java base into the into the
包含Java基础到
container setting up the environment
容器设置环境
variables and now is creating the the
变量，现在正在创建
docker image and if we look at our
泊坞窗图片，如果我们看看我们的
images here we can see that that our
图片在这里我们可以看到，我们的
custom run time has reduced by an order
自定义运行时间减少了一个订单
of magnitude compared to the full JDK
与完整的JDK相比数量级
nine run time here and that that's in
九个运行时间在这里
part because Alpine Linux is so small as
部分原因是Alpine Linux很小
well we get the benefits of a small
好吧，我们得到了一个小的好处
custom run time there and a small size
自定义运行时间，体积小
of the operating system so now we can
操作系统，所以现在我们可以
list our modules in there and we see we
在那里列出我们的模块，我们看到了
only have Java base there so that is an
那里只有Java基础，所以
example of how you can create small
如何创造小小的例子
custom run time images all of the
所有的自定义运行时映像
commands and the docker files and the
命令和docker文件以及
scripts that I've run and used are
我运行和使用的脚本是
available at the end of this
在此末尾可用
presentation so you can you can try this
演示文稿，您可以尝试一下
out for yourself so let's go back to the
自己动手，让我们回到
presentation and just finally at the end
演讲，最后终于
so just to review I showed how Java is
所以只是回顾一下，我展示了Java是如何
improving its execution or running
改善其执行或运行
within docker containers and how you can
在Docker容器中以及如何
reduce the size of JDK 9 in docker
减少Docker中JDK 9的大小
images and so next steps you can go to
图片等，接下来您可以转到
download the JDK from the links here you
从这里的链接下载JDK
can join the open JDK mailing list and
可以加入打开的JDK邮件列表，并且
you can follow us on Twitter I hope you
您可以在Twitter上关注我们，希望您
enjoyed this thank you so much
非常喜欢这个谢谢你